Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development Records UA009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Audiovisual materials, 1920 -- 2011; 1926 -- 1980; UA009.011; 3.7 Linear Feet; 119 Digital Object(s)
  - Ruggles Street Nursery School, Pre-nap song time, 1940; UA009.011.DO.02091 (Box Shared 31)
  - Stearns Village Nursery School [Stathy Efstathion pictured], 1960-11-01; UA009.011.DO.02092; Carr, Edward F. (Box Shared 31)
    Pictured: Stathy Efstathion, 3 yrs. old
  - Nursery Training School of Boston, students at play, 1945; UA009.011.DO.02093; Zilinsky, Anthony (Box Shared 31)
  - Columbia University Professor [Dr. Ernest Osborne] visits Boston Nursery School, 1943-10-25; UA009.011.DO.02094; Merrill, Richard (Box Shared 31)
    Text on back: Dr. Ernest Osborne of Teachers College, New York, visits the Ruggles Street Nursery School in Roxbury, Mass., one of the oldest pre-school centers in the country, while attending the 10th biennial conference of the National Association for Nursery Education, Oct. 22-25 1943.
    Child Development; photographic print
  - Renaming Ceremony, Miss Davies and Mrs. Schell pictured, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02095; Keller of Belmont (Box Shared 31)
  - Renaming Ceremony, Mrs. Schell and Mrs. Davies pictured, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02096; Keller of Belmont (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - A. A. Eliot resignation party, 1952; UA009.011.DO.02097 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Nursery Experts at School, 1948; UA009.011.DO.02098 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Text on back: To learn improved ways of working with young children, these Greater Boston teachers are taking the summer program at the Nursery Training School in Boston. Dr. Abigail A. Eliot, extreme right, diredtory and Miss harriert nash, right, kneeling, consultant on early childhood education, Connection Education dept., are among the faculty; further names of all pictured on photograph.
    Child Development; Eliot, Abigail A.; Nash, Miss Harriet
  - Image of Miss Abigail Elliot, Miss Martha Elliot, Mary Ellen Cannon and Mary Edgerton, 1952-05-29; UA009.011.DO.02099; The Boston Globe (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Music class, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02148 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Children and the War, 1945; UA009.011.DO.02149; Merrill, Richard (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Ruggles Street Nursery School of the Nursery Training School of Boston, 1935; UA009.011.DO.02150 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Stearns Village Nursery School, image of George Gordon, 1960-11-01; UA009.011.DO.02151; Carr, Edward F. (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Story time at Ruggles St. Nursery School, 1942-01-02; UA009.011.DO.02152; Wayne, Ralph (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Text on back: "Tell us a story", the eternal request of children, is being answered at the Ruggles Street Nursery School in Roxbury by Barbara Buckley of Ansenia, Conn., "Ruggles Street", which will celebrate its 20th birthday Jan. 13-14 and is one of the oldest nursery schools in this country, will benefit from the Greater Boston $7,600,000 War Fund Campaign.
  - Diane Calesa and Willliam Martin, two children at play, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02153; Merrill, Richard (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Abigail Eliot and Miss Dorothy Kieth with children from the Brooks School, 1956; UA009.011.DO.02154; Duette (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot, Abigail A.; Kieth, Dorothy
  - The Clark Hill Nursery School, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02155 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records
  - Queen Mary and Abigail Eliot at the Rachel McMillan School in London, 1921; UA009.011.DO.02156 (Box Shared 29)
    Child Development; People; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Eliot, Abigail A.; Queen Mary
  - Nursery Training School of Boston, UA009.011.DO.02157; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Nursery Training School of Boston
  - Ground breaking of Eliot Pearson, 1962; UA009.011.DO.02158; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - Nursery Training School classroom, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02159; Merrill, Richard (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Instructor is Ruth Taylor Stone, an early childhood educator at the Nursery Training School of Boston and the Eliot-Pearson School.
  - Eliot-Pearson School, UA009.011.DO.02160 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Buildings; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records
  - Ruggles Street Nursery School of the Nursery Training School of Boston, 1935; UA009.011.DO.02161 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; People; Ruggles Street School; Nursery Training School of Boston
  - Miss MacDowell, health director, UA009.011.DO.02162 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; People; Eliot-Pearson Dept. of Child Development
  - Child being walked to the Nursery Training School of Boston, 1930; UA009.011.DO.02163 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; People; Nursery Training School of Boston
  - Children at Nursery School, 1956; UA009.011.DO.02164; Duette (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Children; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Eliot-Pearson Children's School
  - Children at play in the nursery school, 1939-01-23; UA009.011.DO.02165; Egan Photo Service (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
  - The Clark Hill Nursery School, UA009.011.DO.02166 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Clark Hill Nursery School
  - The Clark Hill Nursery School, children on the playground, UA009.011.DO.02167 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; People; Clark Hill Nursery School
  - The Clark Hill Nursery School, fingerpainting children, UA009.011.DO.02168 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Children; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Clark Hill Nursery School
  - Children used in the Christian Science Monitor, 1961; UA009.011.DO.02169 (Box data_value_missing_25e4d1092ca6c6f174e7bc7e4e26e284)
    Child Development; Children; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records
  - Marjorie Manning, UA009.011.DO.02170 (Box Shared 32)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Manning, Marjorie
  - Children playing with beads in the playground, 1930; UA009.011.DO.02171 (Box Shared 32)
  - Class of 1932, Nursery Training School, UA009.011.DO.02172 (Box Shared 32)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; People; Students; Nursery Training School of Boston
  - Clark Hill Nursery School, child painting, UA009.011.DO.02173 (Box Shared 32)
  - The Clark Hill Nursery School, 1940; UA009.011.DO.02174 (Box Shared 32)
  - Mary Frank, President of Council, 1954; UA009.011.DO.02175; Zitso Studio (Box Shared 32)
    Child Development; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; People; Frank, Mary
  - Children on their way to Ruggles Street Nursery School, 1935; UA009.011.DO.02176; Keller, Robert J. (Box Shared 32)
    Child Development; Children; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Ruggles Street School
  - Nursery School Trainees having tea, 1949; UA009.011.DO.02177; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box Shared 32)
  - Three women having tea in the Margaret W. Thacher Library, 1964; UA009.011.DO.03009 (Box Shared 33)
    People; Libraries; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Eliot-Pearson Children's School; Eliot-Pearson Dept. of Child Development
  - Women looking through observation windows, 1964; UA009.011.DO.03010 (Box Shared 33)
    People; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Eliot-Pearson Children's School; Eliot-Pearson Dept. of Child Development
  - An unidentified woman addressing a group of women in a classroom, 1964; UA009.011.DO.03011 (Box Shared 33)
    Evelyn Pitcher, educator and chair of the Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Study and Human Development stands in front of the class.The person in the front row,third from the left with her hand up to her chest, was identified by Priscilla Harcourt to be her eldest sister Dr. Mary Ruth (Johns) Fox, MD. She led a distinguished career as a pediatrician for 25 years in the first HMO, Group Health, in Washington, DC.
  - The Eliot-Pearson Children's School, ca. 1964, UA009.011.DO.03012 (Box Shared 33)
    3x5
    Buildings; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Eliot-Pearson Children's School; Eliot-Pearson Dept. of Child Development
  - A bulldozer turning-up the grounds around the Eliot-Pearson Children's School, 1963; UA009.011.DO.03013 (Box Shared 33)
  - Five unidentified people located in a crafts room, 1964; UA009.011.DO.03014 (Box Shared 33)
  - Construction of the Eliot-Pearson Children's School, 1963; UA009.011.DO.03015 (Box Shared 33)
  - Students of the Ruggles Street School, 1930; UA009.011.DO.03016; Jacoby, Roy J. (Box Shared 34)
    People; Students; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Ruggles Street School; Eliot-Pearson Children's School; Eliot-Pearson Dept. of Child Development
  - Students of the Ruggles Street School relaxing, 1940; UA009.011.DO.03017 (Box Shared 34)
    People; Students; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Ruggles Street School